{"_id": "beeae70b", "question": "How do I take care of a person who suffered stroke disease?", "answers": "It is lovely that you want to learn. Speak with the doctor and therapists about specific precautions.\nRemove throw rugs and clear the floor of things one might trip on. Install hand rails around stairs and grab bars in the bathroom/shower/toilet.\nEncourage him/her to do whatever s/he can do safely. Falling is common and can cause serious injury because normal reflexes to protect the head don’t always kick in. Another brain injury could cause further damage.\nFind tools that help the person be independent. For example, a “rocker knife” will let him/her cut food with one hand, so s/he doesn’t need someone to cut his/her food into bite sized pieces.\nRecovery will continue for the rest of his/her life if s/he continues to work on improving and if s/he is permitted to try. I climbed six storeys on Saturday because the elevator was out of service. My husband had said “you can’t do that” but I could and I did. I held tightly to the rail and took a break on the last landing to regain my breath, but I made it.\nGive them time to master skills — don’t assume they can’t do something just because they are awkward initially. We are survivors not victims."}
{"_id": "95b1e55d", "question": "Is it really true that blood groups other than O type are more prone to heart attack and heart/stroke diseases?", "answers": "There is an association with heart disease and non-O+/- blood groups. The exact reasons are not known, so causation has not been established. The increased risk is less than 10%.\nYour Blood Type Could Be Linked to a Higher Risk of Heart Attack or\nStroke"}
{"_id": "fde6fb92", "question": "What are some useful tips for living a normal life with Stroke DISEASE?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "595a06ea", "question": "Is stroke linked to Alzheimer's disease?", "answers": "No, strokes don’t cause Alzheimer’s.\nHowever, Alzheimer’s is just one type of dementia, and there are quite a few other types, with the largest being “mixed”, or Alzheimer’s and something else. And what a stroke can do- besides causing dementia, itself- is speed up the damage going on in the brain when any kind of dementia is already present.\nAnd, keep in mind it is thought Alzheimer’s is “present” but undiagnosed because it just hasn’t gotten to the point it is interfering with life, up to ten years before such interference, so that, a stroke in that ten or-so year period can make it seem it was the cause of Alzheimer’s. It likely wasn’t; it just sped up the damage.\nAvoiding a stroke is one of the top five ways to avoid any dementia. Doesn’t mean no-stroke-no-dementia, just that stroke is, itself indicted in some forms of dementia."}
{"_id": "d560ef77", "question": "Can you get a stroke from having aortic valve disease?", "answers": "Yes but that depends on what sort of aortic arch “disease” your talking about. If it’s a congenital coarctation malformation,Aortic stenosis, aneurism or aortic stricture it can cause areas of restricted or pooled blood flow. Technically yes anytime you slow dwell time in blood vessels tiny emboli can develop. In the case of the Aorta it can cause emboli to get thrown up the carotid artery and cause strokes (Aka emboli or embolic showers) in the brain. Often if this is discovered it’s highly recommended to take long term anticoagulants. Surgery or minimal invasive procedures are often recommended.\nI want to stress that although concerning, this kind of disease can be well monitored managed and followed up on. You may need to see one or more specialists. Find a good health provider doctor,nurse practitioner or physicians assistant and start with a full health physical H&P (history and physical exam) People can live long relatively healthy lives with Aortic arch problems."}
{"_id": "947ab37d", "question": "What are the exercises to prevent heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "Sometimes, muscle mass exercise, aerobic exercise, and lung health can greatly effect the health of the heart.\nThe health of the heart, is related to the lungs.\nExercise, aerobic exercises of all sorts, promotes the formation of capillaries, and vessels and additional blood supplies through vessels that only happens through stress and exercise that promote the formation of.\nSome of those of outside capillaries that can grow and give vessels to supply oxygen to the heart muscle. (On the outside of the heart muscles to provide capillaries and then oxygen)\nExercise can spur that in the body.\nHeart disease is a lot of things, genetics, and damages, many things not under the control of the individual.\nThe heart muscle cells, not not regenerate, so things that had and adverse effect, the heart muscles and cells does not recover or regenerate.\nExercise, can create or spur other capalery effect on the outside of the heart muscle to feed them, with good nutrition and exercise.\nA very slight affect, but real effect, to feed the existing heat cells, with oxygen through capalery growth.\nAerobic activity, and types of exercises stresses the system and stimulates the body to produce capillaries, to create new ones to feed organs like, such as the heart muscle."}
{"_id": "4dba3508", "question": "What can I do to reduce my risk of heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "See , if u have hypertension or high cholesterol , feel angina pain in chest where heart is situated , than better take necessary precautions by doing pranayaam that is breathing exercises in yoga and do it properly looking in u tube , do it regularly , but before that 40 min of warm up exercises at home is must and do it gently according to your age , physiological status …..u can take advice of some yoga experts….\nHave light , nutritious , delicious diet full of vitamins and minerals , but eat little less , eat little 4 times so that it will not put pressure in your heart , oil and salt are enemies of heart so avoid having oily spicey , junk food , alcohol , smoking , stress , over burden of work at home .\nEat less salt and sugar , have fruits but wash them properly with water , have lot of oranges , lemon juice water in empty stomach in morning , maintain hygiene , have liquid diet , no overeating of food ….all these factors will help to maintain your health. Get check your bp level and sugar levels if possible . And u can take advice from doctor too in phone . Some people having cardiac problems on doctor's advice keep sorbitol or aspirin at home if u feel severe pain keep one of these under your tongue , but take doctor's advice first , i am not doctor so i can't advise u …..\nHence quality food and physical exercises , meditation help to cope up with such problems….Thank you……"}
{"_id": "f0148c18", "question": "I want to try the paleo diet, but it claims that potatoes are bad—and doesn't red meat cause strokes and other diseases?", "answers": "While many on the paleo diet do not eat potatoes, many certainly do. Often the level of starches/carbs is based on someone's goals and activity levels. Higher levels of activity = higher carb intake. Sweet potatoes and white rice are usually the go-tos but white potatoes have their place as well. Additionally there is evidence that white potatoes in the form of resistant starch\ncan be beneficial for gut bacteria.\nAs for red meat causing diseases (as many others have pointed out) this is nonsense. Don't determine your diet by what the headlines say is the latest superfood or what food is going to kill you. Its bullshit. Do your homework.\nThe paleo diet has never been about re-enactment, its a framework for living an optimal life based on human appropriate food, movement, sleep, etc. Over the past few years, the \"paleo diet\" has evolved to be more about real, whole foods than the previous strict dogma. Many folks have started including beans, potatoes, etc. based on their tolerance to these foods and overall health goals.\nFind out what works for you and don't get hung up on the minutiae."}
{"_id": "5e9376dd", "question": "Can intermittent fasting prevent heart diseases and strokes?", "answers": "There is a growing body of evidence showing it can reduce the risks of a number of ailments.\nHowever, these studies are not perfect - they have their own limitations, including limited sample sizes, high dropout rates among study participants, as well as debates over exactly how intermittent fasting should be done in order to reap measurable benefits.\nKey sources to explore:\nNot so fast: Pros and cons of the newest diet trend - Harvard Health\nFasting boosts stem cells’ regenerative capacity\nIntermittent fasting - healthy or hype? | American Society for Nutrition\nIntermittent fasting promotes adipose thermogenesis and metabolic homeostasis via VEGF-mediated alternative activation of macrophage"}
{"_id": "e868e222", "question": "Is stroke a hereditary disease?", "answers": "Stroke is not hereditary, but there are some inherited conditions that can cause stroke. One example is cerebral autosomal dominant arteriopathy with subcortical infarcts and leukoencephalopathy (CADASIL). Read more about it at: http://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/condition/cerebral-autosomal-dominant-arteriopathy-with-subcortical-infarcts-and-leukoencephalopathy"}
{"_id": "09bf7072", "question": "What are foods that prevent heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "20 Foods That Can Help Prevent Heart Disease\n1 – Fresh Herbs\nWhen you add these to foods instead of salt and fat, you’re making a heart-healthy choice. They add flavor without the bad stuff. Spices and other foods are delicious ways to eat heart-smart.\n2 – Black Beans\nMild, tender black beans are packed with heart-healthy nutrients. Folate, antioxidants, and magnesium can help lower blood pressure. Their fiber helps control both cholesterol and blood sugar levels. Add beans to boost soups and salads.\nPrep Tip: Rinse canned beans to remove extra salt.\n3 – Red Wine and Resveratrol\nIf you drink alcohol, a little red wine may be a heart-healthy choice. Resveratrol and catechins, two antioxidants in red wine, may protect artery walls. Alcohol can also boost HDL, the good cholesterol.\nTip: Too much alcohol hurts the heart. Don’t have more than one drink a day for women or two drinks for men. It’s best to talk to your doctor first. Alcohol may cause problems for people taking aspirin and other medications.\n4 – Salmon: Super Food\nA top food for heart health, it’s rich in omega-3s. Omega-3s are healthy fats that may lessen the risk of heart rhythm disorders and lower blood pressure. They may also lower triglycerides and curb inflammation. The American Heart Association recommends two servings of salmon or other oily fish a week.\nCooking Tip: Bake salmon in foil with herbs and veggies. Toss extra cooked salmon in fish tacos and salads.\nBy The Way There is More\nSource: NY Times"}
{"_id": "9d76154c", "question": "Is it true that there is no proof of cholesterol lowering drugs lowering the rates of heart attacks and strokes? Instead, there is proof that consuming cholesterol lowering drugs contributes to the risks of having other diseases like diabetes, etc.", "answers": "I am a scientist, and the only thing that matters to me is evidence, and quality of evidence matters most. Although your question is prejudicial, I will try to answer it nevertheless.\nFirstly, there actually is robust evidence that cholesterol lowering drugs, called statins, have a statistically significant causal effect on lowering the risk of cardiovascular disease. A systematic review (considered the pinnacle on the hierarchy of biomedical research\n), published by the Cochrane Collaboration\n, concluded that:\nOf 1000 people treated with a statin for five years, 18 would avoid a major CVD event which compares well with other treatments used for preventing cardiovascular disease. Taking statins did not increase the risk of serious adverse effects such as cancer. Statins are likely to be cost-effective in primary prevention.\nSystematic reviews roll up results from a large number of clinical studies, in this case 19 studies, to remove bias and other issues. In this case, statins clearly save lives.\nFurthermore, the standard of care of most healthcare plans state that aggressively treating cholesterol in patients leads to better outcomes. Which means the healthcare plan is spared the expense of paying for angioplasty, stents, bypass surgery, and other expensive medical procedures.\nAs for stroke, statins have shown no significant causal effect on the risk of stroke. However, modern evidence-based medicine attacks stroke risk independent of cholesterol levels.\nWith respect to adverse effects,\nthere is no robust evidence that supports a causal effect between statin use and diabetes. In fact, diabetes is, in itself, linked to cardiovascular disease.\nthere is no robust evidence of a causal link between statins and cancer.\nthere is some evidence of rare and reversible cognitive decline with the use of statins. Once it is recognized by the physician, the FDA urges that the patient not receive the medication any longer.\nthere is also some evidence of muscle pain with the use of statins. However, there are a lot of confounding factors, like diabetes and high blood pressure, which could be linked to the muscle pain.\nI know it’s cool for some people to criticize the use of statins because of some huge Big Pharma conspiracy. Unfortunately for them, the real scientific and clinical evidence contradicts those claims.\nOh one more thing. Science doesn’t “prove” anything – it makes provisional conclusions based on evidence supporting or nullifying a hypothesis.\nMathematics, albeit a science, uses proofs, which are inferential arguments within a mathematical statement."}
{"_id": "4c13b768", "question": "How do I prevent hypertension, heart disease, diabetes and stroke?", "answers": "IHigh blood pressure is also known as hypertension. Blood pressure is the amount of force exerted by the blood against the walls of the arteries as blood flows through them.\nblood pressure is the most common problem which is faced by 30% of the population of the world.\nIf left untreated or uncontrolled, high blood pressure can cause many health problems. These conditions include heart diseases, vision loss, stroke, and kidney disease ,\nCauses\nThe risk of developing hypertension increases as people age.\nThe heart is a muscle that pumps blood around the body.\nBlood that has low oxygen levels is pumped towards the lungs, where oxygen supplies are replenished. The oxygen rich blood is then pumped by the heart around the body to supply our muscles and cells. The pumping of blood creates pressure.\nIf a person has high blood pressure, it means that the walls of the arteries are receiving too much pressure on a constant basis.\nThe causes of high blood pressure are divided into two categories:\nEssential high blood pressure: This has no established cause.\nSecondary high blood pressure: There is an underlying cause.\nEven though there is no identifiable cause for essential high blood pressure, there is strong evidence linking some risk factors to the likelihood of developing the condition.\nMost of the causes below are risk factors for essential high blood pressure. There are also examples of secondary high blood pressure:\n1) Age\nThe older you are the higher your risk of having high blood pressure. www.healthpot9.blogspot.com"}
{"_id": "760baea9", "question": "What type of disease is a stroke?", "answers": "A stroke occurs when a blood vessel in the brain ruptures and bleeds, or when there’s a blockage in the blood supply to the brain. The rupture or blockage prevents blood and oxygen from reaching the brain’s tissues.\nAccording to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), stroke is the fifth-leading trusted Source cause of death in the United States. Every year, more than 795,000Trusted Source U.S. people have a stroke."}
{"_id": "840594b8", "question": "Is a stroke considered coronary artery disease?", "answers": "It is not. Coronary arteries supply blood to the heart tissue only. Strokes occur in the brain, far away from the heart.\nHowever, both result from ischemia in the target organ and are caused by very similar mechanisms of hypertension that primes arteries for atherosclerosis which decreases blood supply to tissues, and unstable plaque, ruptured by hypertension, that then forms a clot which blocks blood delivery to either a part of the brain to provoke a stroke or an area of the heart to provoke a heart attack. Hemorrhagic strokes are also common.\nA stroke is a cerebral artery (cerebrovascular) disease or an ischemic brain disease while a heart attack or angina pectoris is a coronary artery or an ischemic heart disease. Both are cardiovascular diseases as they involve the heart’s action on blood vessels and blood vessel’s impact on the heart’s action."}
{"_id": "bef45c2b", "question": "What is the mechanism of action of citicoline? Why is it used in the treatment of Alzheimer's disease and stroke?", "answers": "Citicoline (Cytidine-5′-diphosphocholine or CDP-choline), an intermediate in the biosynthesis of phosphatidylcholine (PtdCho), is one of the cell membrane components that is degraded during cerebral ischaemia to free fatty acids and free radicals.[1]\nIt increase the brain phosphatidylcholine, which is important for brain function. The therapeutic action of citicoline is thought to be caused by stimulation of PtdCho and sphingomyelin synthesis, and by inhibiting the destructive processes (activation of phospholipases)in the ischemic brain[2]\nCiticoline neuroprotection may include-\npreserving cardiolipin (an exclusive inner mitochondrial membrane component) and sphingomyelin;\npreserving the arachidonic acid content of PtdCho and phosphatidylethanolamine;\npartially restoring PtdCho levels;\nstimulating glutathione synthesis and glutathione reductase activity;\nattenuating lipid peroxidation;\nrestoring Na+/K+ATPase activity.[3]\nCiticoline also provides choline for synthesis of neurotransmitter acetylcholine, stimulation of tyrosine hydroxylase activity and dopamine release.\nCiticoline: (a) acetylcholine, PtdCho, AdoMet and GSH biosynthesis and (b)␣sphin- gomyelin synthesis.[4]\nFootnotes\n[1] Cytidinediphosphocholine (CDP-choline) for cognitive and behavioural disturbances associated with chronic cerebral disorders in the elderly.\n[2] Citicoline: neuroprotective mechanisms in cerebral ischemia\n[3] Citicoline: neuroprotective mechanisms in cerebral ischemia\n[4] Citicoline: neuroprotective mechanisms in cerebral ischemia"}
{"_id": "5526115b", "question": "What's the point of learning a new language if you can get Alzheimer's disease or have a stroke and lose all of that knowledge?", "answers": "What's the point of being awake? What's the point of knitting? What's the point of cooking? What's the point of a hot bath? What's the point of watching Doctor Who? What's the point of falling in love? What's the point of literally anything?\nThings have value intrinsic to themselves and to you, at that time and place in your life. That they may not be as important in a different time and place in your life is both okay and, I feel that this is important to say, doesn't negate their value they held. They still hold that value, and they always will.\nWhy? Experience changes us. Surely that means something. Experience means the exact people that we influence directly and indirectly are influenced pretty directly by our experiences in life.\nI learned ASL as a Deaf child of 13. From that led to this very moment right now where I'm writing this, fully aware that that choice affected every choice from there. It has meaning and it has value."}
{"_id": "2357315a", "question": "Can sickle cell disease cause a stroke?", "answers": "Yes lack of oxygen from the sickled red blood cells can cause stroke, children are checked from 2 to 17 to see if they have a propensity for stroke by using transcranial doppler testing. If found that they are likely to having a stroke they begin chronic blood transfusions or blood exchanges in effort to keep the oxygen flowing consistently to the brain."}
{"_id": "d9421e2d", "question": "Does eating one meal a day cause diabetes, stroke and heart disease?", "answers": "It depends not only on how often you eat, but also in what you eat. If you don’t eat fast-absorbing carbohydrates (as in refined flour, white rice, potatoes) and instead eat fat, protein and fiber rich meals (or slow carbs like in lentils, beans or chick peas), your blood sugar will not have big spike.\nThese foods are also more filling than carbohydrate rich foods and will help control hunger better, not the other way around.\nI would not eat once a day because I like stopping for a meal (and eating) and I don’t see many advantages to eat besides time saving.\nThat being said, the refered article is vague and outdated in my opinion, as it does not make any reference to which kind of diet it is talking about."}
{"_id": "a77dcfa4", "question": "Which autoimmune disease can cause a stroke?", "answers": "Behçet's disease (BD) can cause stroke. It’s a chronic, systemic vasculitis that can cause stroke.\nAny vascular disease affecting multiple systems increases the chance of TIAs or stroke\nOthers include:\nBuerger's Disease (Thromboangiitis Obliterans)\nEosinophilic granulomatosis with polyangiitis (EGPA, formerly known as Churg Strauss)\nCryoglobulinemia.\nGiant Cell Arteritis\nHenoch-Schönlein Purpura\nMicroscopic Polyangiitis\nPolyarteritis Nodosa\nPolymyalgia Rheumatica\nRheumatoid Vasculitis\nTakayasu’s Arteritis\nGranulomatosis with Polyangiitis (GPA, formerly known as Wegener’s)\nI will have missed many other Vasculitis. For instance, Cerebral autosomal dominant arteriopathy with subcortical infarcts and leukoencephalopathy (CADASIL) should be included even though it’s technically not multi-system, but is contained as vasculitis mainly in the brain.\nCerebral Autosomal Dominant Arteriopathy (CADASIL)"}
{"_id": "207f692f", "question": "My mother's obese. She is a recovering stroke patient and has coronary heart disease. How can I know if she's taken in just enough food in her diet?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ba51f51a", "question": "Is heart stroke a disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "490fe01e", "question": "What does it mean to die from heart disease that is not a stroke, when you have diabetes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "443c1b68", "question": "How do I avoid heart disease with a long family history of heart attacks and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "62c4c341", "question": "Why is it that female hormones are thought to protect against heart disease, but to be the cause of strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d3a85695", "question": "Can a sudden start to exercise after months of physical inactivity cause a heart disease/stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "741c5766", "question": "How do you start to reverse heart disease without risking a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2a7783f6", "question": "Are there specific CPT codes for stroke and heart disease to report to my insurance company claim that covers stroke and heart disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8bfc00a8", "question": "Are strokes related to ischemic heart disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5b8ac0b1", "question": "How are hypertension, heart disease, and stroke related?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "59af7840", "question": "What do you think of the Norwich Medical School study that Omega-3 fish oil supplements offer \"little or no benefit against cancer and heart disease\" and no benefits at all against diabetes, anxiety, depression, and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6d58630f", "question": "Should a patient who've recently had a stroke also get evaluated for asymptomatic coronary artery disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "697187f1", "question": "What should be the everyday vegetarian diet plan for preventing heart disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d73fd35c", "question": "What are some herbs to eat that are known to protect against heart disease, heart attacks, and strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f78fd3de", "question": "What is the outcome of a disease called? For example, what would the tumor be called in cancer or a stroke be classified as, strokes and tumors are caused by disease and not diseases.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2bd77c9b", "question": "What tests should I have, and how often, to monitor my risk factors for developing heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "28171918", "question": "How many diseases can occur due to a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6639c624", "question": "Why are cancer patients at a higher risk of dying from heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "46822b19", "question": "The use of gene therapy in fighting disease has been incredibly powerful, particularly in cancer. What diseases are being fought by gene therapy today? How will such therapy medicine in the next two decades?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c04ad8c9", "question": "I have neuropathy, heart disease, diabetes, high blood pressure and have had numerous strokes. How can I exercise?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "afdaef13", "question": "Does it make sense for God to make a planet where humans get painful diseases and why would he do that? Cancer, coronavirus, strokes, dementia. Thoughts?", "answers": "If I may, I’d like to answer with a few starting assumptions that can lead you to an answer to your question based on the beliefs and knowledge that gave meaning and joy to the lives of three good women we’ve lost this last year, at least during our time on earth.\nHere are the beliefs that I know all three shared that can serve as a starting point (premises, if you will) for your consideration of the answer I’d like to offer at the end:\nGod is the embodiment of perfect love\nWe are God’s children in the sense that God is the Father (Creator) of our spirits, having created us from eternal, pre-existing intelligence - namely the raw energy of our will, mind, and awareness.\nGod gave us free will from the beginning of our existence as spirits.\nIn God’s glorious presence, where there can be no evil, pain, suffering, illness or death, our innocent spirits could never have learned good from evil because there was no evil.\nGod created this Earth to be separate from God’s presence, as a training and proving ground for His children. We are living in a fallen state as a result of the transgression of the first of God’s children - Adam and Eve - when God put the “breath of life” (spirits created by God) into their homo sapiens human bodies.\nGod has given each of us free will and innate moral sensibilities to accompany the gifts of reason, intelligence, and creative capacity in this life to LEARN good from evil and the consequences of each. Good = Peace, love, joy, truth, faith, and life. Evil = Conflict, hatred, lies, pain, suffering, and death. Etc.\nWe all sin, and are thus forever unworthy.\nSo God sent His Son to a human mother in order to atone for our sins and take upon Himself the infinite sufferings and pain and injustice from all the sins and evil of all mankind, that we can repent of our sins and through baptism accept God’s grace and the cleansing power of the symbolic blood He shed for us.\nThrough faith, learning, and prayer, we gain access to incredible truths about this temporary state we’re in that teach us to choose the good (which comes from God) and eschew the evil (which comes from the Father of Lies, aka Satan).\nSo illness, disease, suffering, and more are a natural result of the fact that we are living in a fallen state.\nAs we are now learning (through the work of Dr. Martin Seligman and the Positive Psychology\nmovement), science is beginning to catch up with and reinforce the positive principles of hope, optimism, and positive thinking - consistent with what I’ve learned from the time I was a child as a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, which principles I’ve articulated above.\nEven if you’re currently hostile towards religion, you might want to consider that science and common sense will tell you that there are certain beliefs and attitudes and knowledge that help anyone thrive even under whatever difficult conditions or circumstances that life may throw at us. Even the threat of impending death need not hold us as victims bound by fear. I will soon share examples.\nI would simply assert in all sincerity that anyone who has faith in a loving God who will help us overcome evil, pain, and suffering has an enormous head start in being positive, thriving, and recovering no matter what may come our way.\nIn the past year, I lost my mother-in-law (March ‘20), favorite aunt (August ‘19), and sister-in-law (July ‘19) - all to cancer, although I believe my mother-in-law died from undiagnosed COVID-19, since three of her caregivers tested positive, and one, her son, was hospitalized with COVID-19 and thankfully recovered).\nMy point is that every one of those noble women faced their death with faith, peace of mind, hope and joy. There is no reason whatsoever that we must view cancer, coronavirus, strokes, or dementia or any of the trials of this life with fear, angst, or bitterness.\nInstead, trust in God’s love and His promises of eternal life through the salvation offered by His Son, Jesus Christ. Turn away from the nihilistic betrayal of hope represented by the modern lies perpetrated by the foolish who define faith as belief in that which is contrary to reason rather than the way God defines faith: as trust in those truths that can’t be seen (i.e. known by the senses and logic alone). There is no conflict between faith and reason, or between true religion and true science.\nSo consider instead the faith, hope, and love offered by these loved ones we’ve lost this past year:\nMy Mother-in-law, Ann Danes.\nMy mother-in-law, Ann Danes, a widow, spoke of her longing to once again embrace her parents and husband in the spirit world after her release from this mortal “vale of tears.”\nI’ll never forget the blessing of her visiting us here in Utah not long before her diagnosis, and the wisdom she shared with our family.\nWhile in hospice care, she had a steady stream of friends and family visiting her and caring for her. She was playing the piano for as long as she had strength. To know Mom was to love her.\nOn Christmas, in the cold of Kuna, Idaho, she insisted we bundle her up and push her around in her wheelchair, surrounded by most of her 8 children and a lot of grandchildren, as we visited home after home singing the carols of hope and joy in the advent of a baby 2,000 years ago who would save us all from death and those who repent from sin.\nShe was a great lady, and when she hugged you, you KNEW you were loved.\nMy Wife Kathy with her sister, Annette Hiatt\nMy sister-in-law, Annette Hiatt, a cancer survivor since the ‘90s, inspired so many in the support groups she frequented, and changed the nature of the hospice care she was given, that they will be naming a care facility after her in Idaho Falls.\nAnnette inspired all of us during her decades-long fight with cancer, with her love of life, her readiness to laugh, her unfailing service to everyone fortunate enough to be around her, and all she did for her eight children and can’t-count-em-all grandchildren. My favorite memory is when she visited her gravesite and asked for a picture of her to be taken laying on her plat. Can’t find that picture, but this one gives you a good feel for her indominitable sense of humor about the lung cancer (that started as breast cancer) that made it so hard for her to breathe and ultimately took her life:\nNote the sign that says “Out of Order.”\nMy aunt Darla touched tens of thousands of lives through her writing while she was alive, and continues to bless lives with her writing even now that she’s gone. Read what my beloved aunt wrote about her decision on how to spend the last few months of her life, and the courage behind her faith: What My Journey with Cancer Is Teaching Me\n.\nMy Aunt, Darla Larsen Isackson\nDarla was not spared the trials of life, from the time she was scalded by a kettle of boiling milk as a toddler and almost died. But she learned what God wanted her to learn from her trials, and was an incessant optimist. If you read her article, you will see those lessons on full display.\nHer son Brian, a cousin I loved, ended his own life. Darla wrote a book about it: After My Son's Suicide\n. This nearly perfect lady perhaps understandably struggled with perfectionism, but wrote an article about that too (Satan’s Counterfeit Gospel of Perfectionism\n), prompting an Apostle of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints to quote her in General Conference, calling her an “insightful Latter-day Saint.”[1]\nQUESTION: So why does God allow pain, illness, contagion, suffering, evil, death, loss, injustice, and all manner of wickedness amongst his children to torment our lives and afflict our hearts and minds?\nANSWER: To produce inspiring women of grace and love like those I’ve just described, through a refiners fire of facing and conquering all of the trials and tests of life. Truly they were loving daughters of a loving Father in Heaven.\nAnd not to forget - God lets us men who are unworthy of such noble women learn from their example as we strive to overcome our own trials so we can be joined with the women we love and admire, eventually, in the unity of perfect love that our Father wants for each of us after we learn to embrace only that which is good (and leads to joy) and reject all that is evil (and leads to misery).\nThis life is our time to learn those lessons, through faith, study, pondering, and prayer.\nFootnotes\n[1] Be Ye Therefore Perfect—Eventually"}
{"_id": "19e69465", "question": "Sleeping too much (over 9 hours) is said to increase the risk of diabetes, heart disease, and stroke. What is the mechanism behind this?", "answers": "The exact mechanism isn't known but this may be related to being sedentary, eating more, being overweight, having sleep apnoea, poor quality sleep, napping, having experienced chronic stress or depression, all of which increase the risk of metabolic syndrome.\n‘The American Heart Association (AHA) describe metabolic syndrome\nas a “cluster of metabolic disorders,” that includes high blood pressure\n, high fasting glucose levels, and abdominal obesity\n, which, combined, increase the risk of heart\ndisease\n.’\nAre you getting enough sleep… or too much? Sleep and\nstroke\nrisk - Harvard Health Blog\nMetabolic syndrome: Symptoms, diagnosis, and causes"}
{"_id": "866de1b0", "question": "Why does cholesterol increase the risk factor for heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "Cholesterol is a type of fat found in many foods that come from animals, such as meat and dairy products. Your liver also makes it. Your body needs some cholesterol, but too much can block your arteries. That's why adults with high cholesterol are more likely to have heart attacks and stroke. Several health conditions, your lifestyle, and your age and family history can increase your risk for heart disease. These are called risk factors. About half of all Americans (47%) have at least 1 of 3 key risk factors for heart disease: high blood pressure, high cholesterol, and smoking. Go to my Profile and you can find all about Heart Disease material there..."}
{"_id": "74ee0e9f", "question": "What's the best way to prevent the risk of a stroke or heart disease in a family that has a long history of such?", "answers": "don`t smoke, lose weight, exercise, eat healthy, control your blood pressure. Do it by changing your habits but if you don`t acchieve your goals you will have to take medicines also. So you need to do whatever everybody needs to do but … better. You have an increased risk for vascular disease and, since you cannot change your genes, you have to reduce your risk by changing anything that can be changed."}
{"_id": "e0bdd8d1", "question": "How do I overcome high blood pressure, stroke, and heart diseases in a natural way?", "answers": "Losing your excess stored fat pounds and becoming leaner by moderately reducing your daily calorie intake, choosing to eat only healthy, fresh foods, avoiding alcohol, and adding exercise to your day (an hour’s worth of aerobic or resistance exercise) is the natural way to lower your blood pressure, and lower your risk of having a stroke or developing heart disease."}
{"_id": "db6fad9a", "question": "Can suffering from a stroke be classified as one of the comorbidities of disease?", "answers": "Yes as you go from normal functioning to possible inability to move certain parts of your body or speak clearly. A comorbidity pertains to a disease that exists stimultaneously with or worsens or affect the primary disease but suffering is how your mind takes on the disease as part of how you handle the disease and not necessarily a comorbidity as this is an attitude. An attitude is not a disease unless the disease causes despair from suffering because you can’t communicate or move, both of which relate to the disease. You have a choice to suffer or not (by accepting the stroke) but it can lead to mental illness (despair or suicide).\nOne thing that will happen to anyone is the grief process as you learn to accept the primary disease and this will happen to anyone with loss of any kind. So there will be depression as part of the stages of grief like loosing a loved one (or a part of yourself) but this is temporary and leads to acceptance not. Dealing with a disease, it is wise to read Elisebeth Kubler Ross’s Five Stages of Grief and know that is a normal route for all of us when confronted with disease that we have difficulty handling."}
{"_id": "1d57e5fe", "question": "Are there any scientifically proven natural alternatives to Warfarin? I have a rare congenital blood clotting disease which requires me to be on Warfarin since that disease was first diagnosed in 2008, followed 8 weeks later by an ischemic stroke.", "answers": "No. Warfarin is a very well understood drug. It's a mess to take, but it does exactly what it's supposed to. Any natural remedy that had the same level of precision would very quickly become a medical drug. However, many warfarin patients today switch to other, newer medical drugs that weren't around in 2008. Talk to your doctor about it would be my suggestion."}
{"_id": "a8e19776", "question": "Is it dangerous to stroke a cat? Can you get a disease because of just touching a cat?", "answers": "Depends on the cat and what their body language looks like at the time. There are some exceptions to the rule, but in general the chart below is pretty accurate. For a strange cat, I would only pet between the 1–2 range on this chart. For a familiar cat, you can typically push it to the 3–4 range if trying to sooth the cat, however at this point I would call the cat and let them come to you if they *want* to. Never push pettings on a cat above 1–2 if they don't voluntarily come to you, or you risk making the cat feel trapped / man-handled.\nFor some cats their show of displeasure at being petted when they didn't really want to be is not all that offensive — if I pet or pick up my current cat when she wasn't really looking for that level of attention, she kinda squeaks like a toy and pouts. For my last cat, if you reached toward her when she wasn't ready, she would get very ornery, up to and including scratching.\nSo go slowly, and watch the cat’s body language. Remember to stroke from head to tail, never in reverse unless you know the cat and they are fond of such a thing — otherwise you may annoy them, especially directly after they've licked their coat clean, because you're ruining their “do”.\nOh — and don't let them smell your fear."}
{"_id": "21b7b8e8", "question": "Does yoga solves heart problems?", "answers": "Yes.\nYoga has cure for many problems ,a man face in day to day life.\ncoming to the heart problems, there are different types of heart problems ,may be different symptoms, the best solution for this is PRANAYAMA.\nThere are many pranayama(think 7 related to reduce these heart problems), in which\nAnulom vilom pranayama\nkapalabathi pranayama can hep you a lot.\nThere are other pranayama even you can practise daily and can observe lot of improvement.\nPranayama is the breathing technique which\nRemove the negative energy, toxins from our body and gives positive energy.\nPranayama improves the blood circulation, which is very important for the heart to pump properly.\nPranayama calms the mind\nCures anxiety and depression\n.\nPranayama releases stress and depression.\nRemove artery blockages\nSeven pranayama for heart patients.\nBhastrika Pranayama\nKapalbhati Pranayama\nBahya pranayama\nAnulom Vilom Pranayama and Nadi Shodhan\nBhramari Pranayama\nUdggeth Pranayama\nPranav Pranayama\nYoga poses for heart patients.\nUttanapadasana\nPavanamuktasana\nShavasana\nI think shavasana is the easiest asana one can practise daily.\ncaution: don't sleep in savasana:P (almost every one does in the starting).Just try to concentrate only on your breath.\npeople who have heart problems should not practise these asanas.\nparipurna navasana\nUtthita Trikonasana\nFor breathing exercises,to know about pranayama and benefits refer to this link Seven Pranayama, Breathing Exercises and Benefits\nAnd there will be a lot of difference if change your diet with yoga.\nI personally attended yoga classes and saw many people who had major diseases like cancer,heart diseases and people who have problems in their kidneys, gallbladder, and many more people with different problems got cured and living happily:)\nHope it helps.\nsource,image source:Google"}
{"_id": "c515d963", "question": "Is COVID-19 a disease of clots, strokes, and rashes?", "answers": "Many autopsies suggest that. A lot of clots, strokes, and rashes may have been coming anyway in patients predisposed to those conditions. I bet if there were autopsies performed on traffic deaths we might still find those 3 conditions because most of the western world populations are predisposed to these conditions being gluten and oil consumers which are part of the rashes, clots, and strokes. It’s like asking is COVID a disease of grey hair? On the surface yep."}
{"_id": "ce74a6b3", "question": "Why do optimistic people have a better disease outcome from health problems such as stroke, heart attack, and cancer?", "answers": "Such a state of mindfulness begins very early in life when one - together with one’s siblings - seem pretty never get too much illnesses as the general people around . And when everyone in the communities have had vaccines for all the various ailments and diseases , one appears to be immune to diseases like TB MALARIA TYPHOID GASTROENTERITIS or any of the viruses that may be going about - makes one feel less fearful ; And as one grows to maturity and beyond such a state of mindfulness remains together with the healthy lifestyle which comes naturally - such as vigorous regular exercises.\nHence such optimism starts very young and waxes with growth into old age . At 79 - 80 in 5 months , I have no old age afflictions . However so saying - Only last week I went down with the flu - courtesy of my dear most loving Boss-lady - who so generously coughed and sneezed full blast beside me while I was driving her to the doctors, in a closed up window -put paid to me. Yet I bounced back within 5 days . I’m good now ! I wish I could have pretended for a few weeks … but she’ll soon sus me out . OK ALVIN ?"}
{"_id": "81baca0f", "question": "Should I not learn a new language in fear that I might get Alzheimer's disease or have a stroke? Why or why not?", "answers": "First of all, your stroke may hit any place that’s in your brain. Any place. The language centers are on the left hemisphere brain. I previous learned three languages in my childhood. I forgot ALL of them. I was in America, so I heard a lot of English. I tried speaking in broken-down English for my writing and for my oral. I know a woman who was injure on the emotional complex of her RIGHT hemisphere brain. We were in a stroke center, together."}
{"_id": "43813afe", "question": "Can celiac disease cause a stroke?", "answers": "Not particularly.\nIf it is untreated, then the resulting mineral and vitamin deficiencies might.\nCeliac disease results in damage to absorbtive surface of the gastrointestinal tract which leads to decreased absorbtion of iron and vitamin B12.\nIron deficiency anemia is a risk factor for stroke as it causes a compensatory increase in number of platelets predisposing to stroke.\nVitamin b12 deficiency increases homocysteine levels in blood again predisposing to stroke (Dont remember the exact mechanism)\nIf the resultant malabsorbtion is minimal either due to early detection and inititation of gluten free diet or due to supplementation, then there is no significant risk."}
{"_id": "cef159b1", "question": "Which cuisines are the most healthy and the most unhealthy in terms of prevention of obesity, heart disease, stroke, diabetes, and hypertension?", "answers": "Abstract—— Obesity has been shown to be an independent risk factor for coronary heart disease. The insulin resistance associated with obesity contributes to the development of other cardiovascular risk factors, including dyslipidemia, hypertension, and type 2 diabetes. Choose foods low in saturated fat, trans fat, and sodium. As part of a healthy diet, eat plenty of fruits and vegetables, fiber-rich whole grains, fish (preferably oily fish-at least twice per week), nuts, legumes and seeds and try eating some meals without meat. Select lower fat dairy products and poultry (skinless). Go to my Profile and you can find all about Hypertension material there..."}
{"_id": "d12e1a58", "question": "Can Graves' disease narrow the blood vessels and cause a stroke?", "answers": "Yes, that's what Graves disease does. Stay on any medicine the doctor has you taking and use Fish oil supplements, this allows blood to move more freely in the vessels. Also take Folic acid(Vit.B3),this will clean out the narrowing vessels and making it less likely for you to have a stroke."}
{"_id": "129b3bef", "question": "Can the feeling of a clogged ear have any relation to heart disease, stroke, high blood pressure, or type 2 diabetes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f0c32db3", "question": "How do I treat a stroke, and why do many people who are old experience this disease?", "answers": "Call Emergency Services immediately if you even suspect a stroke. There are no “home cures”. Even the doctor cannot treat it in his office. Time is brain. The sooner your loved one gets to the Emergency Room, the sooner they can be diagnosed and treated and the more brain function that can be preserved.\nMy co-worker called 911 because she was concerned about me. I was sitting in the Ladies Room, feeling nauseous. The EMT’s quickly suspected stroke, bundled me into the ambulance and rushed me to the hospital. They’d called ahead and medics met the ambulance. The rushed me straight into the CT machine and I was told I had a bleed in my brain. Time from 911 call was about 15 minutes.\nThe ER neurologist told my husband that my coworker had saved my brain and possibly my life with her call."}
{"_id": "fe2c6fb5", "question": "Is it fatty food enough convincing risk factor for cardiovascular disease and stroke?", "answers": "Fatty food is one of the root causes of all heath hazards primarily affecting our cardiac health.. In general there are many risk factors for cardiac health problems including stroke. So yes it is a risk factor but not the only one. There are many factors which combinedly result in it. Some of them on which I can put reflection are sedentary life style, genes of ur father n forefathers, some metabolic effects etc.."}
{"_id": "0acb4653", "question": "Modern humans have between 2 to 5% of Neanderthal DNA in their makeup and it is thought by some, that interaction with them 60,000 odd years ago now contributes to serious human ailments such as cancer, heart disease and strokes. Is this possible?", "answers": "Modern people in many places (including the US) have some ‘mixed’ ancestry if you define that as having genetic variation derived from more than one distant place (like Europe, India, Asia, Africa). This is because there has long been some inter-breeding (and the populations aren’t totally isolated from each other). So the 2–5% figure is no surprise but even that depends on first defining what counts as ‘Neanderthal’. Neanderthals, for example, were just Europeans at some particular time in the past that we, as anthropologists, define by giving them a name.\nEvery region’s genomic variation includes some that involves susceptibility to diseases, usually also depending on lifestyle factors (like diet). So there is nothing particularly risky about ‘Neanderthal’ DNA compared to other DNA. The kinds of late-onset diseases that you mention are mainly affected by lifestyles and we know that a lot of that is recent and has nothing to do with distant ancestry. Further, as these diseases generally strike late in life, and most humans in the Neanderthal (and, indeed, until recent) times didn’t live long enough to get them, so they basically aren’t ‘disease’ genes (and, technically, you should refer to disease-susceptibility genotypes or alleles in some copies of genes, not ‘genes’ themselves).\nSo, generally, there are many subtle assumptions built into your question, and are widespread in thinking and writing about these past times, but should be more carefully thought-out."}
{"_id": "dc59f38d", "question": "Is gum disease linked to stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bd3191f9", "question": "Neurological diseases such as stroke and mental disorder can also make you feel dry mouth and thirsty? Is it true?", "answers": "It cannot only cause the feeling of dry mouth and dehydration it can cause actual dry mouth and dehydration. Damage to the portion of brain where autonomic function takes place will cause the body to fail to hydrate properly. It can cause dryness in the skin, the eyes, the mouth, and everywhere else you can imagine not wanting that much dryness. This takes place in diseases such as Parkinson's. Lewy Body dementia includes a type of Parkinson's and sufferers frequently have extensive dental decay because the lack of saliva allows food to remain on the enamel"}
{"_id": "01e48162", "question": "Has COVID and lockdown created a pandemic of health-related incidence of strokes, heart disease and obesity?", "answers": "No.\nAs an example Scotland has a population about 5 million, and usually about 1,000 to 1,200 deaths a week depending on time of year. National Records of Scotland have been publishing data on excess deaths by cause of death (as stated on the death certificate) by week. (The graph below is for the weeks up to the end of June. They stopped publishing these numbers when ‘excess deaths’ fell to noise level.) It shows the number of Covid-19 deaths, which are all ‘excess’ because it did not exist last year. It also shows a consistent drop in the number of deaths from other respiratory diseases, a consistent increase in the ‘Others’ category, but not any significant change in other causes. (See the dark grey bars below the ‘0’ line which indicate 30–40 fewer deaths per week for ‘Respiratory’ compared to the corresponding week of an average year.)\nThe drop in ‘Respiratory’ deaths may be because the Covid-19 precautions also cause a decrease in other respiratory infections, or that people who would otherwise be dying of other respiratory conditions are instead succumbing to Covid, or both, or something else entirely.\nThe ’Others’ category has shown a consistent increase. This number is not broken down further at this point, but is often dominated by accidental deaths by trips and falls at home and accidental overdoses."}
{"_id": "0bb2066a", "question": "Do you believe that Luke Perry's unexpected death from a stroke at age 52 will help educate fans to cardiovascular disease?", "answers": "It depends why he stroked. I have not got cardiovascular disease, yet I have had 7 strokes. I have a clotting disorder. Perhpas he had a hemorrhagic stroke.\nThey have not released the details, so one shouldnt assume it was because of a poor lifestyle."}
{"_id": "bec312ca", "question": "Which disease's symptoms are high pressure, brain stroke and bleeding in brain? Many people are dying with the symptoms like these. People are thinking it's corona but after testing it, it isn't. I think it's some other disease. What is it?", "answers": "What do doctors say?\nWhoever Is suffering with these symptoms, needs professional medical assistance and care, not guesses from random people on social media.\nTake whoever that is to an ER immediately or phone the Emergency Medical Technicians in your area.\nWishing this person healing and wellness."}
{"_id": "e31b4006", "question": "Humans now live over three times as long as we did when our species first emerged. If we cured the top killing diseases such as cancers, stroke, and brain diseases, how much further could science extend human life expectancy?", "answers": "I don’t think it’s easy to “cure” diseases like cancers, stroke, and brain diseases. Each of these ailments have multifactorial causes, and even within each of these diseases, there are many different types, which also have multifactorial causes.\nFor instance, there is no one, universal cure for cancer. Every cancer has a unique etiology and thus requires different modes of treatment. Because human bodies vary in so many ways, two people will not react exactly the same to the same regimen even if they are diagnosed with the same cancer type and stage. Also, while there can certainly be a genetic component or predisposition for a certain type of cancer, predisposition does not always equate manifestation. This is because inheriting a faulty gene may not be enough to trigger cancer; a series of genetic mutations must accumulate to develop into a diagnosable cancer. Most cancers have no known genetic predisposition. One thing people can do to lessen the chance of developing cancer is to quit smoking or never pick it up to begin with.\nStrokes and brain diseases—also very broad diseases. People can be genetically predisposed to having strokes or brain diseases. Diet plays a role. Infections from bacteria, viruses, parasites, prions as far a brain diseases go. You know what can help decrease your chance of having a stroke though? Quit smoking or never pick it up to begin with.\nAs an aside, there are certain diseases that have been thought to confer some kind of resistance to other diseases. This is best typified by sickle cell anemia, which is much more prevalent in areas where malaria is endemic. While being homozygous for the alleles that confer the sickle cell trait can be particularly damaging and shorten life expectancy, heterozygous individuals have been found display some kind of resistance to the Plasmodium parasite which causes malaria.[1]It’s possible that sickle cell and malaria being prevalent in similar regions is purely coincidental, or there could have been some kind of evolutionary advantage to passing on the sickle cell allele in some instances.\nSo how easy is it to eliminate a disease? Sure, there are definitely, many, many diseases that don’t and ought not confer any kind of evolutionary advantage. We’re still trying to figure that out.\nFootnotes\n[1] Sickle Cell Anaemia and Malaria"}
{"_id": "57e38ed1", "question": "Could baths lower the risk of heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0f8ba833", "question": "Why does too much sleep increase the risk of diabetes, stroke, and heart disease?", "answers": "One guess would be that many people who sleep an excessive amount are more sedentary, and inadequate exercise is a known risk factor for these disorders."}
{"_id": "0f0c6023", "question": "Why do irregular sleep patterns put people at an increased risk of stroke, diabetes, and heart disease?", "answers": "Circadian rhythms. So simple it is. When you observe the nature, everything is happening in regular cycles with different lengths. Days. Months. Seasons. Years. Moon cycles. Sun cycles. Galactic cycles. It goes on and on.\nWith a biological system, it is the same. As it lives, it adapts to changes. It is natural. This adaptation is orchestrated by elaborated brain centers.\nThe problems arise when those cycles got messed up for whatever reason.\nThe body allocates time for activity, eating, digestion, resting, and sleeping. When we do not allow to settle a stable cycle(s) a whole range of troubles arrises.\nIt does not mean that cycles of the body cannot change. But it must be in the way that we adapt to the requirements of our bodies and not vice versa."}
{"_id": "94cf2155", "question": "Can amyloid beta oligomer detector such as antibody 5E3 also detect earlier Alzheimer's Disease for patients having a stroke before?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "897ea216", "question": "Will artificial intelligence be able to accurately predict future heart disease and strokes?", "answers": "Computers that can teach themselves from routine clinical data are potentially better at predicting cardiovascular risk than current standard medical risk models, according to new research at the University of Nottingham.\nThe team of primary care researchers and computer scientists compared a set of standard guidelines from the American College of Cardiology (ACC) with four 'machine-learning' algorithms – these analyse large amounts of data and self-learn patterns within the data to make predictions on future events – in this case, a patient's future risk having of heart disease or a stroke.\nThe results, published in the online journal PLOS ONE, showed that the self-teaching 'artificially intelligent' tools were significantly more accurate in predicting cardiovascular disease than the established algorithm. In computer science, the AI algorithms that were used are called 'random forest', 'logistic regression', 'gradient boosting' and 'neural networks'.\nDr Stephen Weng, from the university's NIHR School for Primary Care Research, said: \"Cardiovascular disease is the leading cause of illness and death worldwide. Our study shows that artificial intelligence could significantly help in the fight against it by improving the number of patients accurately identified as being at high risk and allowing for early intervention by doctors to prevent serious events like cardiac arrest and stroke.\n\"Current standard prediction models like the ACC are based on eight risk factors including age, cholesterol level and blood pressure but are too simplistic to account for other factors like medications, multiple disease conditions, and other non-traditional biomarkers. These AI algorithms have the potential to help save more lives\".\nProfessor Jon Garibaldi and Dr Jenna Reps, of the Advanced Data Analysis Centre in the School of Computer Science, said: \"We were curious to find out how four modern machine learning algorithms would perform given the large data set of 378,256 patients from nearly 700 UK GP practices. Indeed, we think this is the first large scale investigation of this type using routine clinical data.\n\"Our results show that 24,970 cardiovascular events occurred over a 10 year follow-up period. Compared to the established risk prediction algorithm, all four algorithms improved overall prediction accuracy, from 1.7% to 3.6%, as determined by a metric called the 'Area Under the Receiver Operating Characteristic curve'. The highest achieving algorithm (neural networks) correctly predicted 7.6% more patients who eventually developed cardiovascular disease compared to the standard algorithm.\"\nThe study concludes that the improved predictions offered by self-teaching algorithms are better at predicting the absolute number of cardiovascular disease cases correctly, while successfully excluding non-cases. The research team believes AI has a crucial role to play in the devising of healthcare tools of the future which will deliver personalised medicine, tailoring risk management to individual patients.\nThe team says improvement in predictive accuracy could be further explored using machine learning with other large clinical datasets, in other populations, and in predicting other disease outcomes. But future investigation of the feasibility and acceptability of machine-learning applications in clinical practice is needed before any real life clinical application of this new technology is rolled out.\n“CodesRoom” Provides trainer for AI Development to increase professionals in the world."}
{"_id": "6b282185", "question": "Can we put a stent in brain blood vessels to cure diseases like stroke or brain infarction?", "answers": "It can be one before a brain infarct to prevent the same. It is a reasonably standard option for internal carotid lesions in the neck. It is not much harder to get a tiny catheter into arteries in the brain but because of both size consideration and the fact that lesions in the major vessel at the base of the brain are rarer than ICA issues n the neck it is very rarely done.\nAneurysm in the brain may be treated by a variety of techniques from inside the arteries.\nDone after more an couple of hours a brain infarct placing a stent is a bad idea that has a risk of causing fatal bleeding in the brain.\nThis is the reason it is critical for stroke victems to get immediately to hospital."}
{"_id": "57bef5ae", "question": "Why do oily food, greasy food, and spicy food increase the chances of heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "Oily food and greasy food has a large amount of fats. so after going in the lymphtaic system it is stored in the form of fat molecules which move through the blood to the adipose tissues. If the quantitiy of fats increases then the cholestrol level also increase . So when the blood is carried to the capillaries these fat molecules can cause blockage as the space is too narrow and when these reaches to the heart the flow of the blood gets difficult .\nSpicy food leds to indigestion. No proper digestion of food leds to diarrhea. As the stomach is not able to accept the food the HCL increases and causes acidity. After going to the intestine the walls of the intestine is not getting hold of the food and therefore not digested. These kinds of food move away without providing any nutrients to the body.\nif you like my answer you can upvote it or comment to ask other quries"}
{"_id": "351394aa", "question": "What are my chances of recovery from smoking-related diseases such as cardiac disease, lung cancer, chronic pulmonary disease (including emphysema), and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "589fc32d", "question": "How may climate change increase your risks of asthma, heart disease, and stroke?", "answers": "Climate changes can impact the air we breathe in. As temperatures increase, warmer air helps in the formation of ground ozone in the form of smog, which is a powerful air pollutant. It can irritate the lungs and act like a sunburn on the lungs which can trigger Asthma attacks.\nWith the changes in the climate, wildfires are becoming more frequent and intense. Wildfires produce smoke which produces tiny particles that can travel through the lungs into the bloodstream. Particle pollution can cause asthma, strokes, and even lung cancer."}
{"_id": "bc17af37", "question": "Why is drinking 2 or more diet sodas a day linked to stroke and heart disease?", "answers": "The study being referred to here involved women and showed an association (a linkage as stated) between diet soda consumption and an increased risk of heart disease/stroke. Neither a cause and effect relationship nor a possibly harmful ingredient was established."}
{"_id": "ec3f34bb", "question": "Will a potential cure for cancer be useful in finding a cure for cardiovascular diseases, stroke and brain damage? How can we use the cancer research to find a cure for various other diseases? Is that applicable as a treatment for other diseases?", "answers": "There is mo cure for cardiovascular disease nor cerebrovascular disease purely because the majority of these are caused by an embolism within the blood stream. When the clot travels into a vessel in the heart or the brain it can cause myocardial or macular infarction. The best way to prevent these is to exercise, eat healthily, dont smoke and keep a good mental state. There will be some other diseases that can be cured but using the same methods of cancer curing is likely not applicable to them."}
{"_id": "0d5f3dd4", "question": "Could I challenge the lower risk of heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "38d36b59", "question": "Is a stroke a cerebrovascular disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e8262317", "question": "Do vegetarians have higher risk for stroke & lower heart disease risk?", "answers": "Vegetarians doesn’t mean all is safe, although non-veg have all the more risks to get heart disease, stroke and many others.\nHow you eat a vegetarian meal is cardinal. From simple processing - just heated a bit- to complicated, prolonged processing onfire we are making it increasingly difficult for our body to digest and assimilate food and its nutrients, respectively.\nFood can give us life, death and get us out of even the most intractable life-threatening condition."}
{"_id": "6fbaadf6", "question": "What are the risk factors for carotid disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "533cceb1", "question": "What is the smoking rate in Israel, and what is the incidence of coronary disease, stroke, lung cancer and concomitant morbidity there due to smoking?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "131cff31", "question": "Is it true that adults with gum disease are twice as likely to have a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0f3eaf35", "question": "Can the severity of depression increase the chances of heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9a22fac2", "question": "How is a Keto diet healthy, ie heart disease, stroke, etc?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e51ae7c0", "question": "Does asbestos also cause heart disease, heart attack, or stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "fc9b254a", "question": "As an 18-year-old fit male, should I still worry about cancer, heart disease, and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "17620358", "question": "Don’t most people with a very high blood pressure live completely normal lives, without heart disease, a stroke, or other problems, or do the majority of people with high blood pressure experience medical disaster as a result?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ad765325", "question": "If a person has good genes, does it mean that he or she won’t can’t cancer, heart disease & stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6d823041", "question": "I read if you have fat thighs, you're less likely to suffer heart disease, strokes, heart attacks; is this true?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9d6fe9e4", "question": "What things can assure to prevent heart diseases and strokes? What should we do?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f9a2b2ff", "question": "What are the measures to take in solving the problems of heart diseases and stroke?", "answers": "Heart disease is actually ridiculously easy to cure as is type 2 diabetes. The cure is a whole food plant based diet (veganism).\nThe science is in, you don’t need drugs or medication for the rest of your life, just change your dietary lifestyle. Note, this is not what Dr’s are taught and not what they prescribe, a whole food plant based diet pretty much cuts the need for a Dr and medicine out of your life so it’s the antithesis of western medicine.\nCheck out NutritionFacts.org | The Latest in Nutrition Related Research\nif youd like the data."}
{"_id": "246f07be", "question": "Trillions of dollars have been invested in cancer research and still nothing. When we know that 70% of all deaths are due to heart diseases or stroke, are people dying from these diseases discriminated compared to the people who have cancer?", "answers": "What do you mean, “still nothing”? Cancer survival rates have rocketed.\nEverybody is going to die. Nobody survives many years after 100. The question is not whether you will die, but how long you will live. If doctors save you from cancer at 70, does that mean that they are plotting your death from stroke at 80?\nThe more you cure people of one disease, the more you seem to kill them of other diseases, later. Stroke and heart attack can appear bigger killers because they are sudden and massive, whereas cancers start small. If we catch cancers early, we can destroy them before they massively affect health. Whereas with stroke you are forever condemned to clearing up the mess after the damage has been done."}
{"_id": "17de3524", "question": "I was told that after many years of having restless leg syndrome symptoms, a person may develop high blood pressure, stroke, or heart disease. Is this true and how does restless leg syndrome cause these conditions?", "answers": "Restless Leg Syndrome\nPeople who have restless leg syndrome (RLS) do tend to have other conditions such as cardiovascular disease, peripheral neuropathy, or Parkinson’s disease, but restless leg syndrome does not cause these.\nLyrica, also known as pregabalin is highly effective for your problem and people should get treated because RLS interferes so much with sleep. Here are some other meds commonly used for RSL: pramipexole (Mirapex), rotigotine (Neupro), and ropinirole (Requip),\nI am a big believer that many problems result from some deficiency. I am sure you have already heard about magnesium, but there are others. “A 2014 study found that vitamin D supplements reduced RLS symptoms in people with RLS and vitamin D deficiency” and according to Healthline, “Supplementation with iron or vitamins D, C, or E can help certain people with RLS.”\n(see article, Prevalence and associated comorbidities of restless legs syndrome (RLS): Data from a large population-based door-to-door survey on 19176 adults in Tehran, Iran)\n(see article, The 11 Best Treatments for Restless Legs Syndrome, https://www.healthline.com/health/restless-leg-syndrome/treatments\n)\nthanks for your upvote!"}
{"_id": "8b22c959", "question": "Is it possible that a person who have a psychological & mental disorders could potentially have a cardiovascular disease in the future like stroke & heart ailment?", "answers": "Yes, it is possible, because psychological or psychiatric conditions do not protect against or prevent conditions affecting the rest of the body.\nDoesn't mean that it will happen, or is likely, though. Just means that people with psychological conditions should access all the same preventative healthcare (vaccinations, screening, physicals) as anyone else."}
{"_id": "7ab5ceec", "question": "Could Sumatriptan in higher doses cause a stroke in the population that are at risk of a cardiovascular disease?", "answers": "Even normal doses if you’re at risk!\nI actually have taken care of a patient who experienced a heart attack as a result of taking sumatriptan as prescribed. She had a migraine and took one pill, waited 2 hours (or whatever the directions were) and took another because she still had the migraine and then started getting intermittent chest pain, bringing her to the hospital and after the second round of cardiac enzyme testing it was elevated!\nSumatriptan causes your blood vessels to spasm smaller, which is how it treats the migraine. It is systemic though, which is how it affected her coronary arteries. For people at risk for ischemic stroke, triptans are not recommended for the same reason as those at risk for a heart attack."}
{"_id": "7dd69256", "question": "How can diabetes cause heart disease, stroke, kidney disease, blindness, and nerve damage?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4c6b016b", "question": "Can a person have a stroke only for high blood pressure, not for any other disease and not for sugar or cholesterol?", "answers": "High BP is most common cause of stroke especially haemorrhagic stroke.. diabetes is another one.. usually a diabetic turns hypertensive leading to metabolic syndrome.. which is a double whammy.. watch out for your numbers"}
{"_id": "ccd40b01", "question": "My blood pressure is on average 158/88 yet I’m 22 years old. Am I at risk of stroke or other cardiovascular diseases? How do I lower my BP?", "answers": "A hypertensive crisis is a severe increase in blood pressure that can lead to a stroke. Extremely high blood pressure — a top number (systolic pressure) of 180 millimeters of mercury (mm Hg) or higher or a bottom number (diastolic pressure) of 120 mm Hg or higher — can damage blood vessels. - Warning signs of an ischemic stroke may be evident as early as seven days before an attack and require urgent treatment to prevent serious damage to the brain, according to a study of stroke patients published in the March 8, 2005 issue of Neurology, the scientific journal of the American Academy of Neurology. Erika Allen"}
{"_id": "8784526b", "question": "Is it true that changes in blood platelets triggered by COVID-19 could contribute to the onset of heart attacks, strokes, and other serious complications in some patients who have the disease?", "answers": "I am still not at all certain about this, but at this point I do not believe that the platelets are directly affected by either the COVID-19 virus or the immune response to it. The primary source of this problem is much more likely to be damage to the lining of the blood vessels, which release clotting factors which in turn cause the platelet aggregation and therefore the clots which cause strokes and heart attacks in some cases. Perhaps a haematologist might give you a more definitive and up-to-the-minute answer.\nEarly on in this pandemic, I thought that it was this damage to small blood vessels which was responsible for most of the effects on the lung, and resulted in the curious combination of low blood oxygen levels without much shortness of breath and the ease of artificial ventilation compared to other cases of viral pneumonia, which cause stiff lungs. However, I was wrong: the lack of shortness of breath seems to be due to an effect of the virus on the brain, while the relative ease of artificial ventilation is still unexplained."}
{"_id": "d162ecf2", "question": "Is eating meat, which is high in sulphur amino acids, linked to a higher risk of heart disease, stroke, diabetes and non-alcohol fatty liver disease?", "answers": "While a plant-based diet is generally considered healthier than a meat-based diet in preventing the risk of diabetes, not all meats affect the risk equally. As Professor Koh Woon Puay, Professor of Clinical Sciences at Duke-NUS Medical School (Duke-NUS), and her team found out, higher intake of red meat and poultry is associated with significantly increased risk of developing diabetes, which is partially attributed to their higher content of heme iron in these meats. This study provides the basis for evidence-based dietary recommendations to the Singapore population in mitigating diabetes risk and reducing the healthcare burden of this chronic condition.\nThese findings come from the Singapore Chinese Health Study, which recruited 63,257 adults aged 45-74 years between 1993 and 1998, and then followed them up for an average of about 11 years. The study found a positive association between intakes of red meat and poultry, and risk of developing diabetes. Specifically, compared to those in the lowest quartile intake, those in the highest quartile intake of red meat and poultry had a 23 per cent and 15 per cent increase in risk of diabetes, respectively, while the intake of fish/shellfish was not associated with risk of diabetes. The increase in risk associated with red meat/poultry was reduced by substituting them with fish/shellfish.\nIn trying to understand the underlying mechanism for the role of red meat and poultry in the development of diabetes, the study also investigated the association between dietary heme-iron content from all meats and the risk of diabetes, and found a dose-dependent positive association. After adjusting for heme-iron content in the diet, the red-meat and diabetes association was still present, suggesting that other chemicals present in red meat could be accountable for the increase in risk of diabetes. Conversely, the association between poultry intake and diabetes risk became null, suggesting that this risk was attributable to the heme-iron content in poultry.\nThis is one of the largest Asian studies looking at meat consumption and diabetes risk. While the findings are consistent with other Western studies that have shown that the increased intake of red meat and increase in heme-iron content of diet could increase the risk of diabetes, this study demonstrated the additional risk of red meat attributable to other possible chemicals, other than its heme-iron content. It also suggested that chicken parts with lower heme-iron contents such as breast meat, compared to thighs, could be healthier. Finally, the study also demonstrated the benefit of replacing red meat or poultry with fish/shellfish.\nDescribing the key take home message for the public, senior author of the study Professor Koh said, \"We don't need to remove meat from the diet entirely. Singaporeans just need to reduce the daily intake, especially for red meat, and choose chicken breast and fish/shellfish, or plant-based protein food and dairy products, to reduce the risk of diabetes. At the end of the day, we want to provide the public with information to make evidence-based choices in picking the healthier food to reduce disease risk.\"\n\"Although a number of western studies have consistently shown that red meat consumption should be moderated, this study is highly relevant as it is based on local population and consumption patterns. The findings affirm HPB's recommendation to consume red meat in moderation, and that a healthy and balanced diet should contain sufficient and varied protein sources, including healthier alternatives to red meat such as fish, tofu and legumes,\" said Dr Annie Ling, Director, Policy, Research and Surveillance Division, Health Promotion Board.\nTreatment of type 2 diabetes - Click here to Read"}
{"_id": "dff1e39d", "question": "How has climate change had an affect in strokes or circulatory diseases?", "answers": "It may well have affected the nutrition quality of that which is served and thus the positive effect on the human body.\nThe stress of evacuation often kills the elderly and those with heart/circulatory problems."}
{"_id": "d21572f8", "question": "Which type of cholesterol increases your risk for heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "Tryglycerides, LDL Cholesterol,VLDL Cholesterol are bad for you. HDL Cholesterol is the beneficial one for you, Higher the better!!"}
{"_id": "3a37e573", "question": "My mother has had stroke symptoms for a few days, but doesn't want to go to the hospital because she thinks it's Meniere's disease. Negotiating only makes her close up & angry. What should I do?", "answers": "I mean, you’re not going to like the answer but at this point, it’s permanent anyway if it really is a stroke. There’s only a narrow window of a few hours where you could receive the medication to destroy the clot and if there’s a chance at surgery to remove the clot, it must be done in 24 hours. 3 days or more out, there’s nothing to be done for it other than rehab. The only exception would be if it were a brain bleed and her life would still be in danger.\nIt’s her life. You’ve explained what needs to be done. It’s her call, unfortunately."}
{"_id": "82bb49cc", "question": "What are the best strategies, actions and blood markers of health to bulletproof us against possible future heart disease, heart attacks and strokes? Not taking into account genetic differences as that’s an uncontrollable variable.", "answers": "First the don’t’s:\nDon’t smoke.\nDon’t use illegal drugs.\nDon’t become a frequent flyer at your local fast food strip.\nDon’t become the poster child for a type A personality, always stressing and raging about everything.\nNow the do’s:\nDo drink in moderation (this means no more than one drink, MAYBE two per evening, if that).\nDo exercise. Even a daily walk is better than nothing.\nDo eat unsaturated fat, omega-3’s, lean protein, and vegetables.\nRepeat after me, “I can only do what I can do. I can only control my own behavior.” Keep repeating until you believe it.\nDo get an annual physical, especially once you hit 40. Before that, every other year is probably okay if you don’t have any chronic health conditions, but don’t go from your senior year to the “big Four-Oh” without setting foot in a doctor’s office.\nDo get enough sleep, or as close to it as possible."}
{"_id": "9931f45c", "question": "If all the main natural causes of death were cured, that being stroke, heart disease, cancer, etc. would people live forever until they die in an accident?", "answers": "Stuff just wears out and some parts can’t be replaced. The studies I’ve seen suggest we might live to about 150 or so if all these things were ‘fixed’, but not more than that. And, of course, you’d have to ask yourself, looking at people 100 or more, would you want to live like that for 50 more years. Undoubtedly some would, but I’m not sure I’d be one of them. Many such individuals seem to be perpetually tired. very restricted in activities and wishing they did not have to struggle each day just to keep breathing."}
{"_id": "92e422c9", "question": "Does vaping cause increased risk for heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "Vaping and tobacco smoking both increase the risk of developing heart disease, stroke, type 2 diabetes, Alzheimer’s disease and some other potentially fatal disorders. The increased contribution to risk is proportional to the total accumulated nicotine exposure involved. Some other factors that also contribute to the risk include: stress, an unhealthy lifestyle and diet, consumption of alcohol and coffee and a possible metabolic magnesium deficiency."}
{"_id": "1fc3c93e", "question": "How can excessive use of proteins in diet, especially animal proteins, result in heart disease, osteoporosis, stroke, and kidney stones?", "answers": "The main issue with animal protein is that they may be injected with artificial hormones, they have carcinogenic compounds and fats which may lead to heart disease or cancer.\nHeart disease: Eating lots of red meat and full-fat dairy foods as part of a high-protein diet may lead to heart disease. This could be related to higher intakes of saturated fat.\nA study has also showed that long-term consumption of red meat can increase trimethylamine N-oxide (TMAO), a gut-generated chemical that is linked to heart disease. Findings also showed that reducing or eliminating dietary red meat reversed the effects.\nBone calcium loss: Diets that are high in protein and meat may cause calcium loss. This is sometimes associated with osteoporosis and poor bone health.\nA 2013 study found an association between high levels of protein consumption and poor bone health. However, another study in the same year found that the effect of protein on bone health is inconclusive. Further research is needed to expand and conclude upon these findings.\nKidney stones: a normal human is completely safe from any issues related to kidney arising from protein intake. However, a person with kidney issues should be very careful about the amount of protein consumed."}
{"_id": "2fec6429", "question": "What is frequent tea consumption tied to a lower heart disease stroke and mortality risk?", "answers": "Chinese scientists have discovered that green tea lovers, on average, are less likely to suffer from atherosclerosis, stroke and heart failure, and also live longer than those who rarely drink tea or don't drink it at all. In addition, it seems that consumption should not only be regular, but also for at least 8 years. Frequent tea consumption tied to lower heart disease, stroke and ………………….(Read More)"}
{"_id": "b03783d3", "question": "Will new research on the dangers of diet soda causing heart disease and stroke influence you to quit consuming it?", "answers": "Yes. I’ve stopped all soda at this point. Research has shown people gain weight drinking diet sodas. It appears to be that the artificial sweeteners are still perceived by the body as sugar so it produces insulin. There also might be some psychological effects, making people eat more than they normally would since they believe they are saving calories from the soda."}
{"_id": "b62ef1d1", "question": "I stroked the head of a donkey in a barn, should I worry of getting a disease?", "answers": "No. You should probably go back and stroke a donkeys head again, just to stay healthy. Being in contact with farm animals increases the amount of good bacteria you are subjected to and therefore makes you healthier. Just don't touch much of anything if your hand has open wounds. Then it might be just as dangerous to touch a donkey than it might be to touch a simple door handle. Bacteria is amazing. You never know what you're about to get;D"}
{"_id": "aa470f87", "question": "Is there evidence for the safety of tPA in stroke patients with sickle cell disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "21206c15", "question": "It is now possible to quickly detect brain blood vessel pathology that may result in some psychiatric and neurological conditions such as stroke, some neurodegenerative diseases including Alzheimer’s disease. https://bit.ly/3bMhYAP ?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0d4ff60c", "question": "Does more exercise after 60 decrease stroke and heart disease risk?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a6e81fba", "question": "Why are more middle-aged Americans dying of heart disease and strokes than before?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2c22e288", "question": "Is a stroke considered coronary artery disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b4010337", "question": "Do you think that avoiding inflammatory foods can reduce heart disease and the risk of stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6074dd61", "question": "Is it true that high blood sugar levels may over time increase the risk of several complications such as eye disease, heart disease, and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f0786d4d", "question": "The gene therapy can help us eradicate heart disease, atherosclerosis, brain diseases, stroke, etc. What is the reason that there is no sufficient investment and funding in this area?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2b515587", "question": "Do most people die from something else before ever getting Alzheimer's disease or having a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "af5d103b", "question": "Does a person on a keto diet face an increased risk of heart disease, stroke, cancer, autoimmune conditions and insulin resistance?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f47c2f0f", "question": "Can degenerative joint disease in C1 and C2 in your neck cause irregular heart beat and mini strokes?", "answers": "Clinical evidence has shown that cervical spondylosis can cause sympathetic nerve irritation and associated sympathetic symptoms. And instability at the C4-C5 intervertebral space is the most common type causing sympathetic symptoms, rather than C1-C2. Could it happen at C1-C2? Yes, but it is not as common.\nArrythmias and the Cervical Spine - Clark Chiropractic"}
{"_id": "4601cb47", "question": "What do you do about your parent lying about having a physical illness or disease such as a stroke or cancer for attention?", "answers": "If it’s faking illnesses for attention it’s called munchausens syndrome. If they are also going around from doctor to doctor you can notify her insurance companies fraud department who will look into your claim. I did exactly that and the insurance company got all her doctors together and made sure any ailment she had was to be shared between all the doctors. This scrutiny became too much for her so she moved several hundred miles away got new insurance started all over again. It’s unlikely that it will ever stop."}
{"_id": "363dc925", "question": "What are the five current findings which relate nutrition to cardiovascular diseases and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bf1dc578", "question": "What type of disease can occur during problems in nervous systems?", "answers": "here are some significant diseases can be hpppen during problem in nervous system like migraine, stroke, demantiam, meningitis etc. For the better treatment concern with dr. ranga chelva krishna . for mor details visit their website .\nvisit here :- Dr Ranga C Krishna NY"}
{"_id": "26142072", "question": "Would any one get heart diseases (stroke, attack, etc) soon if they consistently under depression, short-tempered and agitational? What are the chances of picking up other diseases?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b7526b2e", "question": "What are your thoughts on the comment that \"COVID 19 is the worst disease. When they say 'recovered' they don’t tell you that it means you may need a lung transplant or you may get a massive heart attack or stroke\"?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "910bdd64", "question": "Which is the best modern physiotherapy clinic at treating stroke and Parkinson's disease?", "answers": "Mobiphysio is a modern physiotherapy clinic in Coimbatore providing holistic treatment for the patient to recover from injuries, pain and physical impairments. They are best at treating stroke and Parkinson's disease. Their neurological services include stroke, parkinson’s disease , homecare physiotherapy, post-surgical rehabilitation etc.."}
{"_id": "ae584326", "question": "Can taking 1500mg of Bayer (aspirin with caffeine) daily for over a year cause severe damage in a 240lb woman? The woman is 62, a diabetic and has hypertension with no history of heart disease or stroke.", "answers": "Aspirin is a non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug. One of the side effects is stomach upset, and can lead to an ulcer forming. I know because I used a different NSAID drug for a year and gave myself an ulcer. If this person is having chronic pain they should ask their doctor about why the pain is going on for a year. The pain could be from neuropathy and aspirin is not the drug of choice for that. If she has headaches she could be having rebound headaches from the caffeine if she also drinks dark sodas or coffee along with her Bauer aspirin."}
{"_id": "a3f83f3c", "question": "If a big drug company gives you a drug to cure a disease and it causes problems like cancer or stroke, how do you go after them to get compensation when they refuse to talk to you?", "answers": "They’re not going to talk to you as you are threatening litigation. You’ll need to have a TON of documentation and then find an attorney willing to take the case on a percentage basis as there’s no way you’ll be able to afford the legal fees."}
{"_id": "3c7869b1", "question": "Does having a strong heart and a low pulse from cardio exercise reduce the likelihood of heart disease and stroke even if other risk factors are present?", "answers": "Does having a strong heart and a low pulse from cardio exercise reduce the likelihood of heart disease and stroke even if other risk factors are present?\nStudies determine risk and protective factors based on statistical results from populations, not individuals. I could probably dig up studies which would affirm the contention in your question, but these results would not necessarily be indicative your personal risks.\nSince your reason for asking this question is probably rooted in curiosity and/or concern about your own health, you should have a discussion about this with a doctor who can evaluate the protective effects of exercise in the context of your personal and family medical histories."}
{"_id": "2eaf4994", "question": "What is the death rate from Covid-19 likely to be in a year as compared to numbers of people who die each year from cancer, heart attack, stroke and other serious/life threatening diseases in a country or worldwide?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c8d6a8a0", "question": "Has medicine really had an impact on the prognosis of most non-communicable diseases (i.e., stroke, heart attack)? How have the prognosis changed over time?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8d0fbe5f", "question": "Is the average life expectancy in Africa increasing faster than the average expectancy in all the developed nations? If yes, is this because there is less consuption of processed foods? Where is the lowest rate of deaths by stroke, heart diseases?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ba5f0144", "question": "Is there evidence that genetic liability to insomnia increases the risk of coronary artery disease, heart failure and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2698bbe7", "question": "If I have high blood pressure but I do live a healthy lifestyle e.g. exercise, healthy diet, etc. and do not smoke and drink, is my risk for heart diseases like heart attack and stroke still high despite my lifestyle?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a217b01d", "question": "How much would life expectancy increase if we cured the 3 leading causes of death..Cancer, Heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "cee8cb9a", "question": "I am having heart congestion. What are the possible reasons for having such a disease? What are the chances of getting a heart stroke in the future?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2df29cfa", "question": "How can drinking green tea help reduce your risk of heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "588335b6", "question": "Why do insurance companies cancel the policy of pre-existing diseases, especially in the case of heart attack or brain stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "71e874f3", "question": "Do companies have an obligation to help payment of an employee's of medical treatment for diseases such as stroke? (In Indonesia to be specific)", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "fe022e32", "question": "Is it true that 80 percent of strokes and cardiovascular diseases can be prevented by how you live?", "answers": "Most cardiovascular diseases can be prevented by addressing behavioural risk factors such as tobacco use, unhealthy diet and obesity, physical inactivity and harmful use of alcohol using population-wide strategies.\nPeople with cardiovascular disease or who are at high cardiovascular risk (due to the presence of one or more risk factors such as hypertension, diabetes, hyperlipidaemia or already established disease) need early detection and management using counselling and medicines, as appropriate."}
{"_id": "44884a91", "question": "Will there be a cure for stroke and other neurological diseases, including motor neuron disease and multiple sclerosis in the next 20 years?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "400903bc", "question": "People dying from heart diseases and stroke are discriminated on the expense of the rich people fighting cancer. How can we lobby the decision makers and the rich people to donate more money on heart and brain diseases research? Who can do something?", "answers": "Are they?\nPlease correct me if I am wrong.\nHeart disease can be from a genetic predisposition or self-inflicted. Same with stroke and cancer. Cancer has no magical property to determine if you are rich or poor prior to invading your cells. While using the general term 'cancer' you are literally describing several hundred separate diseases. Treatment for one will not necessarily work for another. Even determining what the cancer does does not necessarily translate quickly to treatment options. Thus the significant research budget.\nSignificant resources are spent annually for all of these things. How a person with substantial assets chooses to give to an organization is entirely up to them. If you personally know a wealthy individual, feel free to contact them requesting funds. Their choice to do so is entirely theirs, so make a good argument when you do so. You cannot legislate philanthropy. You can make your concerns known to your local legislators, as they are involved in setting the government fund allocation to specific areas."}
{"_id": "b4cf151a", "question": "Could a cloned brain-in-a-vat be harvested to replace diseased regions of a patient's brain (e.g. the basal ganglia of someone who's had a stroke)?", "answers": "I think the technology to have the body replace those regions itself with stem cells is far more advanced (and safer) than any hypothetical technology for grafting together spinal cord or brain slices.\nIn addition, there are ethical issues to the brain-in-a-vat: how do you know it isn’t potentially sentient? By cutting slices off, how is that different from harming a fetus? How do you know it isn’t ALREADY sentient? You can’t talk to it, but think locked-in syndrome!\nTake all the abortion issues and multiply them by ten."}
{"_id": "0dbc10ad", "question": "New study find if you get more than 300mg of cholesterol from food per day your risk of heart disease and stroke go up 5%. What if you only occasionally consume more than 300mg of cholesterol (like maybe once per week)?", "answers": "Careful, marketing, observational data, routinely misleading and driven for marketing, monetary reasons, not good science.\nCholesterol\nis manufactured by every animal cell\non the planet.\nWhy? Because it is an essential structural component of every animal cell on the planet, including for ALL cells of human beings.\nWhat does cholesterol enable animals to do which plants cannot do?\nAnswer: Rapidly change shape without cell damage, animals to move. Animals can go eat plants, the plants cannot move.\nGiven then fact, do animals, including humans absorb lots of cholesterol from food?\nAnswer: No! A basic homeostatic mechanisms\nrequired to stay alive.\nSince the primary source of all cholesterol in within, would increases in ingestion drive body cholesterol concentrations higher.\nAnswer: Largely No (beyond small transient increases)!\nGiven this fact, if cholesterol in body goes up, what happens to internal cholesterol production?\nAnswer: You guessed it, it goes down to compensate.\nAnother issue: Does cholesterol have anything to do with artery\ndisease\n?\nAnswer: Largely No! As researched for 2–3 decades before finally figured out and published 1950\n; study at least the abstract and notice the date of publication.\nSince lipoprotein\ns (complex protein particles which transport ALL fats in the water outside cells around our entire body) were identified, 1950, as the most important factor involved in artery disease progression over time, ALWAYS matches event rates over time, why was cholesterol promoted as an alternative (though never correct) concept?\nAnswer: Money and power while working (pretending?) to pay attention to the correct issues to help people.\nLipoproteins have long been divided into 5 major classes based on density ranges (what the D in HDL & LDL, two of the five classes) compared with the surrounding water.\nAdditionally, HDL particles have also been divided into 5 major classes and relation to artery disease event rates. On what basis?\nAnswer: You guessed it, by density, AKA size (an inverse of density)\nThis is a complex issue.\nI hope this helps as an introduction."}
{"_id": "e7bf76a4", "question": "How does daily consumption of fresh apples lower the risk of stroke, high blood pressure, indigestion, asthma, cancer, heart disease, diabetes, and other chronic diseases?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2a96b1ad", "question": "What would be the point of learning something new just to have a stroke or get Alzheimer's disease and forget it?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b69b60e9", "question": "What is the link between the Sinovax Coronavac and the increase in coronary heart disease and strokes after injection?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1d0f0a8e", "question": "How many people who work(ed) more than 60hrs/week at Amazon, Tesla or any highly competitive company had strokes or other cardiovascular diseases?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "41e31512", "question": "How can a stroke mimic PSP given the very different durations of the two diseases?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f0e3feb7", "question": "How do you describe a person suffering from leukemia, Stroke, Hypertension, Rheumatic heart disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "81ef5700", "question": "What are the information technology-based ideas that can solve heart diseases and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "86f743a4", "question": "What exactly about alcohol increases your risk for things like heart disease, stroke, etc?", "answers": "Increased calorie intake can cause diabetes type 2 if one has the right genetic make-up. Obesity can lead to increased risk. Liver failure can mess with you clotting factors as can alcohol use which might be more likely to put you in the position to have a hemorrhagic stroke. Alcohol can cause cellular issues which make one prone to cancers of the head and neck, esophagus, bowel."}
{"_id": "0d6926de", "question": "\"Vegans and vegetarians have a lower risk of coronary heart disease than meat-eaters but a greater risk of having a stroke, researchers have found\" is this statement true?", "answers": "There are two types of stroke: majority of patients have ischaemic (lack of blood supply) stroke; only 13% patients have haemorrhagic (bleeds) stroke. stroke.\nUnderlying pathology for coronary artery disease is atherosclerosis, that causes heart attack and ischaemic stroke. High blood pressure is the leading cause of haemorrhagic stroke.\nSo, this question is stemming from the EPIC-Oxford study recently published in BMJ.\nThis study reported increased risk of haemorrhagic stroke, (not ischaemic stroke) with vegans/vegetarians. Also, in this study vegetarians had lower blood pressure than meat eaters, largely excluding high BP as the cause. The study is suggesting lack of nutrients (vit D, bit B12) as risk factors in vegetarian diet.\nMy take on the study: the groups were divided according to whether they were eating meat, fish or were vegans/vegetarians. No assessment was done with respect to the type of foods consumed in each group. A vegetarian largely consuming whole foods made at home would have an entirely different risk profile than a person consuming large amounts of processed food. This largely limits the significance of the increased stroke finding in vegetarian group.\nHow to translate to your life: largely consuming plant-based whole foods and keeping processed foods to the minimum is still the safest approach."}
{"_id": "3d33ce30", "question": "What if a person has hypertension & he took health insurance & if he suffers cardiac arrest/stroke after 1 year, will these diseases be covered in health insurance within the waiting period?", "answers": "High blood pressure can cause many complications. High blood pressure (hypertension) can quietly damage your body for years before symptoms develop. Uncontrolled high blood pressure can lead to disability, a poor quality of life, or even a fatal heart attack or stroke. Share on Pinterest High blood sugar levels can damage blood vessels and nerves, making a stroke more likely. ... People with diabetes are also more likely to have other conditions that increase the risk of heart disease and stroke, such as high blood pressure and obesity. Go to my Profile and you can find all about Hypertension material there..."}
{"_id": "9d0636b5", "question": "What if there is a blood test that can accurately predict whether a person will have heart disease or a stroke?", "answers": "Nope. The labs will show that a heart attack has occurred but as of now, no tests can anticipate one or a stroke. That’s is because both can be caused by a clot in the heart or brain. They are very small. They are also not always a blood clot. Sometimes they are fatty clots. Plaque is also possible. It can break off and travel. A stroke can be caused by a bleed as well as a clot. A bleed occurs when a vessel in the brain breaks open and blood flows out. It requires very little volume as the brain fills the skull. Symptoms occur when pressure builds as more fluid leaks out. Again it doesn’t take much, around 5cc’s or less, noticeable symptoms appear. 10–15cc’s can cause a coma or death."}
{"_id": "5409e3da", "question": "Which perspective would help us to understand the impact of strokes and brain diseases on memory?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "30daa318", "question": "What is considered 'chronic' anxiety? I have now read that chronic anxiety is a cause of heart disease. I have had anxiety off on for about four years and I am now worried that I am at high risk for a stroke/heart attack.", "answers": "Inside of adding more things to worry about, it would be helpful if you would learn how to manage the irrational, fearful thoughts that create anxiety. To deal with this interference in your life I would first see a doctor about some meds to give you immediate relief & then an anti-depressant/anxiety med for the long term WHILE you take the necessary time to change your thinking, sense of confidence & self image through therapy, books & practices like http://meditation….so\nyou can eventually get off the meds. Learning to becoming your own best friend by knowing who you really are is a priority for a worry-free life. You are a winner. You are waking up!"}
{"_id": "b32d536d", "question": "How common do you think Kawasaki disease and strokes are in people with COVID-19 between the ages of 2-30 years old?", "answers": "Just read about that today. Those 2 conditions are quite rare (the strokes coming from consumptive coagulopathy), ordinarily, but are probably related to antigen-antibody effects. Might be related to the cytokine storm that is apparently the cause of the more common pulmonary complications. The immunology of this virus keeps gets more ‘interesting’—and that is not a good thing."}
{"_id": "7f75466b", "question": "Where can I find the PDF version of Put Your Heart in Your Mouth Natural treatment for Atherosclerosis Angina Heart Attack High Blood pressure Stroke Arrhythmia Peripheral Vascular Disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b8ea2b1e", "question": "Why are major diseases like brain stroke, kidney failure, coronery artery disease, etc. on the rise, and how can it be checked?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2e559042", "question": "If we can use genetic engineering to prevent the atherosclerosis (fatty plaques) formation in the first place, will we get rid of heart diseases and strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0e70c51c", "question": "Is it possible that a small number of unidentified genes are the cause of Bodily inflammatory responses responsible for things like stroke, celiac disease and viral mortality vs cholesterol, proteins like gluten, cold/flu/corona viruses etc?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7cc8df28", "question": "If mean LDL cholesterol fell in Europe (presumably due to increased statin use & changed diets - June 2020 Nature article), has this also caused a reduction in deaths from stroke and heart disease in the same area during that same period?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f5ba6206", "question": "Do timelords ever die of illness? Every time the doctor regenerates it’s something exciting and significant that kills him, but do thy ever get cancer, or have strokes or whatever? And would regeneration remove the disease from their body?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2327e1e3", "question": "Can instant noodles lead to heart disease, diabetes, and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e2fd9706", "question": "Do scientists in Italy say that eating chili (hot) peppers slashes the mortality rate from heart attack and cerebrovascular disease (which restricts blood flow to the brain and includes strokes and aneurysms)?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5de1c0e4", "question": "For a family where both parents' side don't have stroke history and both parents lived above 80, what's the likelihood for the kids died from cerebrovascular disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3af1d5cf", "question": "If you go in for a stroke, aspirate/ suffocate, intubated, go into coma, hypoxia & immediate aspiration pneumonia then go into anoxic brain injury/encephalopathy. prior disease was HP. What is listed as cause of death in order?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9b797cd9", "question": "Why does it seem like more young people of my generation (20 to 40 years) in \"first world\" US or elsewhere are ironically getting diseases associated with older people (diabetes stroke heart attack etc?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bb072043", "question": "Am I depressed if I match own symptoms with Google’s symptoms of diseases like tumour, stroke, seizures, hpv, hcv, HIV and tetnus. My symptoms are headaches once a month and weight loss etc?", "answers": "Good afternoon Raja, I am not a health care professional. All I can do is speak from experience with people that I've known who've tried to self diagnose themselves through Google. Often times they get worked up for no reason. You listed a variety of issues regarding health / your health. The internet is a wealth of information but at the same time it cannot do blood tests, MRI's, x-rays etc... My recommendation would be to see a healthcare professional."}
{"_id": "6b50ace1", "question": "What is the most likely cause of a stroke in a 55-year-old male with a BP of 115/70, total cholesterol 160, LDL 90, HDL 45, normal ultrasound of carotid artery, normal EKG and ECG of heart, calcium score 0, and no signs of peripheral artery disease?", "answers": "Question: “What if the most likely cause of a stroke in a 55-year-old male with a BP of 115/70, total cholesterol 160, LDL 90, HDL 45, normal ultrasound of carotid artery, normal EKG and ECG of heart, calcium score 0, and no signs of peripheral artery disease?”\nAre we discussing an actual person who has had a stroke, or is this a test/homework question? With an actual patient, there would be a lot more information that might help someone think about the answer. With a homework question, I think you could figure out the answer pretty quickly by reading a chapter on stroke."}
{"_id": "89066c4b", "question": "Can you tell from looking at a person's facial features or overall physical appearance or total body mass whether or not he/she is at a high risk of getting cancer or diabetes or heart disease or stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "91ad1e1f", "question": "Is it true that eating instant noodles 2 to 3 times a week can lead to heart disease, diabetes, and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5aeb693f", "question": "When making a caregiver's plan for home care, what is the best way to set up goals for the patient? What goals can be for a patient with a degenerative disease, such as ALS/MND or advanced cancer? Or for a wheelchair bound patient with good life expectancy? Or for a patient with a stroke?", "answers": "Well that depends on a lot of things. You need to ask the patient what their goals are for themselves. This is really important for the palliative patient. There's no point in you telling them they should get outside for 30 mins/day or that they should eat healthier etc. Goals for them may be quite personal and should be supported whether or not they agree with nursing/care aide goals. Goals that inspire them are going to be the goals that will have a chance of being successful. Ask the patient what he/she wants to accomplish in a day? What's something they would love to do that they haven't done in a long time? Is there anything they would like to work on improving? Like sleeping environment, how they mobilize, when/what they eat. Think of yourself as a facilitator, help them to achieve the things they feel are important to them."}
{"_id": "f8b80044", "question": "How may climate change increase your risks of asthma, heart disease, and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "950e16ef", "question": "Why must America humiliate her citizens by making them all fat before killing them with diabetes, heart disease, stroke, cancer, etc.?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3b5025f5", "question": "What should one do with a tumor in the deep lobe parotid tail? I had a stroke four months ago & suffered three lung diseases along with a vallecular cyst which could interfere with intubation. How long can we wait & watch?", "answers": "You are not having a good time is an understatement.\nI am afraid only your Specialist/Oncologists advice and your own instinct/decision can be an answer, because there is still insufficient information & no one can tell you unless they are in the room & have all the evidence, visuals.\nI get the impression that depending on where the vallecular cyst is it can be surgically drained - if the Doctors are not willing to do this to open your airways then can they explain why. I also believe if push came to shove they could intubate you directly through the trachea, though you can ask the Consultant exactly how they would do the Surgery for either as there may be options where surgery can be done without full intubation.\nYou can inform yourself by browsing the links, and if you don’t understand anything do searches for better explanations of the terms.\nvallecular cyst at DuckDuckGo\ntumor in the deep lobe parotid tail at DuckDuckGo\ncan parodit tail surgery be done without full anaesthesia & intubation?? at DuckDuckGo"}
{"_id": "96ce1141", "question": "I watch a lot of saturated fats and I’m afraid that I wil devolope heart disease or stroke I’m 16 what should I do to prevent it?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c9d6913f", "question": "I think I have a skin disease, and my mom just stroke it off every time I mention getting it looked at, by saying tomorrow. This has been going on for about a year. I am afraid it’ll become permanent, what should I do?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "dd8545a1", "question": "I was diagnosed with hypertension I'm 23, I feel depressed I'm in pain, how long (statistically) can I live a healthy life without problems like kidney failure, strokes and heart diseases?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b4b87e60", "question": "I had 3 strokes & almost died from lyme disease. Will I always b so tired? I had a pic line. Is it gone? How can I find out? Will it come back?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "267c61df", "question": "I'm a 13 year old girl. I have been struggling with sleep deprivation and depression for two weeks. Is there a chance of developing a heart disease, getting a heart attack, or stroke from going days without sleeping?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "dca6e831", "question": "Why do long working hours increase deaths from heart disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
